The seedling, it sprouted,
这个苗呢 虽然发芽了
but
但是呢
it's not growing properly.
它没有正常地生长
[Maybe it needs]
所以可能需要
[some medicine,]
吃一些药啊
[some injections,]
打一些针啊
and some rest
休息休息
to get back
让它尽快地回到
on the right track.
正常的轨道上来
Then, how about now?
那现在呢
Are the grapevines doing okay?
葡萄苗正常了吗
Most likely.
大概率吧
They're growing normally now.
算是正常生长了
But it's still seven or eight months
但是离结果子
until they bear fruit.
还有七八个月呢
It means that
意思就是说
in another seven or eight months,
再过七八个月
I'm going to have a younger brother.
我就要有弟弟了
Why a brother,
为什么是弟弟
not a sister?
不是妹妹呀
My cousin said you like sour things,
表姑说你爱吃酸的
so it should be brother.
就是弟弟喽
That's pseudoscience.
这是伪科学啊
We can't believe in that.
孩子 咱可不能信啊
Having a baby
生孩子吧
is like opening a blind box.
它就跟拆盲盒一样
You only know the gender
只有生出来了
after it's born.
才知道是男孩女孩的
What about me?
那我呢
The blind box of me,
我这个盲盒
are you satisfied with it?
你开得满意吗
Of course,
满意啊
our Yunjie
我们云阶
is the best.
很好的
You know what,
你知道吗
when you were just born,
你刚出生那会儿啊
your dad held you,
你爸抱着你
I could tell he was really happy,
我知道他特别开心
and excited.
特别激动
[And then,]
然后那个嘴巴
[he just kept grinning.]
就一直咧着
[But he couldn't help crying]
但是那个眼泪啊
[all the time.]
哗哗地往下流
I was so shocked.
我都震惊了
You know?
你知道吗
Really? My dad cried?
真的吗 我爸还哭啊
Really!
哭
[He bawled his eyes out.]
哭得稀里哗啦的
[It's rare to see him like that.]
很少见他那样的
[That's true.]
是呀
Then after "little grape" is born,
那小葡萄出生之后
I'll get to see my dad cry.
我就能见到我爸哭了呀
The point you focus
你这关注的点
is too different with others'.
怎么有点不太一样啊
Little grape?
小葡萄
Who's that?
谁啊
That's how you name it?
你给他起的名字吗
[So, you like to have a brother]
那你喜欢弟弟
[or a sister?]
还是妹妹呀
[Sister.]
妹妹吧
So I can hold her,
这样我可以搂着她
sleep with her,
一起睡
and braid her hair.
还可以给她扎小辫
I can also play with her,
跟她一起玩
and wear matching clothes
还可以跟她
with her.
穿一样的衣服
No, it won't work,
衣服不行
she's too little.
她太小了
You can also watch her do her homework.
你还可以看着她写作业
Right!
对
I can also teach her to play the piano.
还可以教她钢琴
[As she grows up,]
以后长大了
[there will be so many things]
你们一起做的事情
[you can do together.]
会有很多很多的
Your dad's here.
你爸来了
You two ladies,
二位
it's time to head home.
该回家就寝了吧
Dad,
老爸
take a seat.
坐下来
Let's chat for a bit.
我们一起聊会儿吧
Continue chatting?
还聊啊
I heard that when I was born,
我听说我刚出生的时候
you were bawling your eyes out.
你哭得稀里哗啦的
Is it true?
真的吗
You should sell my privacy
为了煽情
to get emotional support.
不惜出卖我的隐私啊
Aren't we family?
一家人嘛
So when my sister is born,
那我妹妹出生的时候
can you cry like that again?
你能也哭给我看一下吗
I've never seen you cry.
我还没见过你哭呢
I can't guarantee that.
那不一定啊
Don't put pressure on me.
不要给我压力
What if I can't cry?
万一哭不出来
That would be so embarrassing.
多丢人哪
Just take it easy, okay?
放轻松 放轻松
Let's wait together
我们一起等待
for that day to come.
那天的到来
Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
Mom's home.
妈妈回来了
[Mommy.]
妈妈
[Sweetheart.]
宝贝
[I'm so sorry.]
对不起啊
[Mom had an overtime today,]
妈妈今天加班
[so I come back late.]
回来晚了
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
You are...?
你是
Hi,
你好
Mr. Yu asked me to come over.
是于总让我过来的
I'm so sorry
真是不好意思
for keeping you waiting so late.
让你们等这么晚
Never mind.
没事的
Mom's back,
妈妈回来了
so goodbye, you guys.
叔叔要走喽
Uncle Yu Chen,
那俞辰叔叔
tomorrow you should tell me the story
明天要给我讲一个
about the Journey to the West.
西游记的故事
Don't worry, Uncle will prepare well.
放心 叔叔好好准备
Okay.
好
Were they well-behaved?
她们乖不乖呀
Definitely.
很乖
Absolutely.
特别乖
[Well, go on.]
你 接着说
[Mr. Yu,]
于总
[that's the situation.]
情况就是这样的
[Thanks to Dr. Yu.]
多亏了那个俞博士
[Otherwise,]
要不然
[I wouldn't be able to]
我一个人
[handle those two kids]
根本对付不了
[by myself.]
那两个小孩
Mr. Yu, I can't do this job
于总 下次这个活
one more time.
我可干不了了
Please spare me.
你还是饶了我吧
I just ask you to
不是 你说我就让你
look after two little girls.
帮我去看一下姑娘
Is it that difficult?
这事有那么费劲吗
You even got an outsider,
你说你还找个外援
a male one.
还找个男的你
It was not me.
不是我找的
It were your daughters
是你的女儿
who wanted to play with him.
自己要和他玩的
[And]
而且
[if without the help of]
如果没有那个
[that handsome guy,]
帅哥的帮忙的话
I even couldn't walk in the door.
你女儿连门都不让我进
They're quite familiar with
人家和那个医生叔叔
that uncle doctor.
还挺熟的
What do you mean familiar?
什么挺熟的呀
Not familiar.
不熟
It's just being polite.
那就是客气
That's because our kids are sensible,
我们孩子懂事
and well-raised by their mother.
这妈妈教育得好
What familiar?
挺熟的
[Mr. Yu,]
于总
I understand what you're saying.
您的意思我明白
Don't worry,
您放心
I've seen all the process.
全程我都盯紧了
[The living room doors]
客厅大门
[were all wide open.]
都全部开着呢
That handsome guy was just
那个帅哥
helping me take care of them for a bit.
只是帮我照顾了一会儿
Then when the kids' mom arrived,
后来孩子她妈来了
he left quickly.
麻溜就走了
That's more like it.
这还差不多
Is he truly
不是什么就帅哥 帅哥
a handsome guy?
帅哥的
Why don't I think so?
我怎么没觉得他帅啊
I think he's quite handsome.
我觉得挺帅的呀
So did you get his WeChat?
那么帅 你加微信了吗
Of course.
加了呀
Everyone wants to have a doctor friend.
谁不想有个医生朋友啊
[What's the issue, Mr. Yu?]
怎么了 于总
Give me your phone.
那个 手机给我
Let me take a look at his Moments.
看一眼他朋友圈
Uh, it's not quite appropriate.
看人朋友圈不太好吧
Mr. Yu.
于总
Aren't
不是
Moments meant to
这朋友圈
be seen
不就是拿来
by friends?
给大家伙看的吗
Right?
对不对
I just want to know
我就为了了解一下
who is with my daughters.
什么人跟我姑娘在一起
Let me take a look.
给我看一眼
[Only 3 days of Moments are visible,]
这还设个三天可见
it's too secretive.
这太不阳光了吧
What does he need to hide?
有什么见不得人的事啊
What kind of normal person
这什么正经人
would set this?
会设这什么三天可见呢
Mr. Yu,
于总
you can't say that.
您不能这么说
My Moments are also the same.
我朋友圈也三天可见
You two seem quite compatible.
你们俩还挺般配的
Really?
真的吗
But
可是
he's so much better than me.
他比我优秀太多了
He's a Doctor of Medicine after all.
他可是医学博士啊
Can't you be a bit more confident?
咱能不能自信点
[You're]
你现在
already working now,
现在都已经开始工作
making your own money,
自己赚钱
and earning your own living.
自己自食其力了
He, you know,
他 你说
a thirty-year-old man,
三十岁的人了
is still a student
到现在
by now.
还是个学生
Right?
对吧
[He is still living off his parents.]
还在啃父母
You're so much better than him.
你比他强多了
I'm telling you, I think you're
我跟你说 我觉得你
the best
在全公司里
in the whole company.
你是最棒的
Really, Mr. Yu?
真的吗 于总
Alright then,
这么着啊
from now on,
以后没事啊
keep in touch with him more often.
这个跟他多联系联系
You're both young people
都是年轻人
and have a lot in common, right?
共同语言比较多 对吧
[From now on,]
从今以后啊
any expenses you have
但凡是你跟他交往
from dating with him,
所有的什么路费啊
like transportation, or...
什么这个 这个 这个
the cost of meals,
吃饭的钱呀
I'll cover them for you.
我都给你报了
[How about that?]
好不好
Okay, thank you, Mr. Yu.
好的 谢谢于总
Well, if there's nothing else,
那 没什么事
I'll head back.
我就先回去了
I have work tomorrow morning.
明天早上还上班呢
Okay.
好
Keep it up.
加油啊
Thank you, Mr. Yu.
谢谢于总
Stay in touch with him.
跟他常联系啊
Okay.
好
[Honey, honey.]
老婆 老婆
[Honey, I was wrong.]
老婆 我错了
[I heard you're not even eating.]
阿姨说你连饭都不吃
[How can you do this?]
这哪儿行啊
[It's not good for your health.]
这对身体不好
[Honey, I apologize]
老婆 我给你道歉
[Don't worry, your child won't starve.]
放心 饿不死你孩子
I'm sorry.
对不起
I sincerely apologize to you.
我认认真真给你道歉
I was wrong.
我错了
No,
不
it was me who's wrong.
是我错了
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
[It's me who should apologize.]
是我应该向你道歉
[I shouldn't investigate you,]
我不应该派人查你
and ruin your image
破坏了你在
in front of your ex-girlfriend.
前女友面前的形象
I shouldn't have
更不应该
messed up your business.
把你的生意搅黄了
I've thought it over seriously,
我认真地想过了
what I did
我这么做
was really wrong.
真的挺不对的
[I'm sorry.]
对不起
Don't be like this.
你别这样
You're suddenly scaring me.
你突然间怪吓人的
Honey,
老婆
[I was wrong.]
我错了
I'm apologizing to you, okay?
我给你道歉还不
It is...
这都
After the child is born,
等孩子生完了
let's just get divorced.
咱俩就离了
Is that okay?
行吗
Honey,
老婆
don't say that.
怎么能说这样的话
Our baby is going to be born.
这眼看就要生了
You think just because I'm pregnant,
你是觉得我大着肚子
so I won't divorce you, right?
不可能跟你离婚 是吧
No, no, no, honey.
没有没有没有 老婆
I don't wanna divorce at all.
真的不能说离婚的事
I'm sincerely apologizing to you.
我跟你认真地道歉
I was wrong.
我错了
Honey,
老婆
I know you love me, cherish me,
我知道你爱我 珍惜我
care about me, so you checked up on me.
在乎我 你才会查我的
Really, honey.
真的 老婆
I'm apologizing to you, honey.
我给你道歉 老婆
Look,
你看
Xiongxiong is seven years old, right?
咱们家熊熊七岁了吧
Our second baby
咱们家老二
is about to be born soon.
马上就要生了
Happy life is
幸福的日子还在后面呢
still ahead.
还长着呢
[I don't want to be with you anymore.]
我不想跟你过了
[You just live with the children.]
你跟孩子过吧
Your good life now
你现在的好日子
can go on without me.
没我也一样过
Honey,
老婆
how can the child not have a mother?
那孩子怎么能没妈呢
Just find another one.
再找个妈呗
Now, anyone can be a mother.
现在谁当妈都行
Your eyes are only on the children,
你的眼里只有孩子
right?
是吧
Honey,
老婆
you are the
你才是我
happiest part of my life.
最幸福的生活呢
[Honey.]
老婆
Your life now
你现在的生活啊
would be better without me.
没有我会更好
You can find another woman,
你再找个女人
and have two more children for you.
再给你多生俩啊
Aren't you wishing for more children?
你不是想多子多福吗
Don't you want
你不是想要
a family portrait full of people?
全家福里站满了人吗
[No, no.]
不是 不是
[Honey, it's not like that.]
老婆 不能这么说
You know Jia Haowen,
你太了解贾浩文
you know your husband very well.
你太了解你老公
My life dream is to grow old with
我的人生梦想就是跟我
the woman I love.
心爱的女人白头到老
My life dream
我的人生梦想
is to have babies with
就是跟我
the woman I love the most.
最爱的女人生宝宝
But I don't want
可是我不想要
this kind of life.
这样的日子
Honey,
老婆
honey, honey,
老婆 老婆 老婆
I was wrong.
我错了
[I shouldn't have met my ex-girlfriend.]
我不该见我的前女友
[Really.]
真的
[I apologize to you.]
我向你道歉
I just went to see her
我为什么要去见她呢
for work.
我就是为了工作
I was wrong. I shouldn't
我错了 我
have hidden this fact from you.
我不该隐瞒你这个事实
I just
我就
thought it's better to avoid trouble.
多一事不如少一事
It's my problem.
这是我的问题
Anything else?
还有呢
And, and...
还有 还有
I shouldn't
我不该
keep her WeChat, I'll delete her.
有微信 我把她删了
I shouldn't message her,
我不该有短信
I'll delete it too.
我也把她删了
I shouldn't contact her.
我不该跟她联系
Is that all?
说完了吗
That's all.
说完了
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
let's get divorced.
咱俩离了吧
Look at Wanzhen,
你看人家婉真姐
even with two children,
带着俩孩子
she still gets divorced.
说离也就离了
Early or late, they divorced.
早离晚离都是离
Honey,
老婆
I'm not like her husband.
我跟她老公不一样
I will listen to you completely, right?
我 我多听你的话呢
But I'm tired.
可是我累了
I want to let go of myself.
我想放过我自己
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
I don't want to tail you anymore.
我不想再盯你的梢
I don't want to check up on you.
我不想再查你的岗
It makes me seem so petty,
显得我特别小气
so foolish.
特别愚蠢
It makes me not like myself.
显得我都不像我自己了
Life is so short.
人生那么短
I want to live for myself.
我想为自己活着
Now I'm just asking for trouble
现在我跟你在一起
to stay with you.
我就是自找不痛快
After the divorce,
离了之后呢
you can do whatever you want.
你爱干吗干吗
It has nothing to do with me.
就跟我没关系了
I'll be free.
我就自由了
I'll be liberated.
我就解脱了
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
just set me free.
你放我自由吧
Honey.
老婆
Haven't you ever thought about it?
你难道没这么想过呀
I annoy you.
我这么惹你烦
I'm so affected.
我这么作
If we divorce,
你要是离了
you'll be free, too.
你也自由
You'll be liberated.
你也解脱
Your life won't have to
你的生活就不用
revolve around me.
围着我转了
You can be in charge.
你就可以自己做主了
No, honey.
不 老婆
I'm willing to revolve around you.
我就愿意围着你转
I'm willing to let you be in charge.
我就愿意让你做主
I don't want to see you anymore.
我不想再看到你了
Just let each other go, okay?
我们放过彼此 好不好
I just want to be with you.
我就想看见你
Don't let go of me.
让你别放开我
Let me go!
你放开
No, honey.
不 老婆
I don't want this family anymore.
这个家我不要了
I'll give it all to you.
我都给你
Honey!
老婆
[Cheers, Mr. Zhou,]
来 周总
[Try this liquor I brought back]
您尝尝 这我从
[from my business trip.]
外地出差带回来的酒
Really?
是吗
What did you gain from the trip?
出差有什么收获吗
There's indeed a huge one.
这次收获太大了
I signed
我签了一个
an operations director
以前在一个大平台
who worked for a big platform.
干的运营总监
This time, our Blue Ocean
这次啊 我们蓝海
is going to upgrade significantly.
就要鸟枪换炮了
Upgrade
鸟枪换炮
significantly?
升级换代
Congratulations.
恭喜
Thanks for your blessing.
谢谢 谢谢 谢谢
Just try the liquor first.
您先尝尝酒啊
Not bad.
不错
Uh,
这个
the era of
新媒体
the wild growth of
以前那个
the new media
野蛮生长的时间
has passed.
已经过去了
[So,]
所以说呢
[the Blue Ocean also needs to]
我们蓝海也得
[upgrade systematically.]
系统性地升级
Otherwise,
不然的话
it will be eliminated
就该被这个时代
by this era.
给淘汰了
That's right.
没错
Be prepared for the future.
未雨绸缪嘛
In the past, the era of the wild,
过去那草莽时代啊
with boldness and unorthodox methods,
胆子大 路子野
one could survive.
就能生存
Now the industry
现在行业呢
is becoming more regulated.
越来越规范了
If Mr. Yu has such
于总要是有这样的
ability and determination,
能力和决心
I think the future of Blue Ocean
我觉得蓝海的未来
is limitless.
不可限量
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
谢谢周总
With your words,
有您这句话
I feel so reassured.
我心里边太踏实了
Cheers.
来
Come on.
加油
Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢
Let's not talk about work today,
那咱们今天不谈工作了
just drink.
咱们只喝酒
Alright.
好的
You see, I always have this problem,
您看我老是这个毛病
all my affairs
这个所有的事吧
revolve around work.
都围着工作走
[I work during the day,]
这白天工作
[and then at night,]
然后晚上呢
[there still are many social events]
好多应酬吧
[that need to be cope with.]
也都是为了工作
In the future, I must learn from you,
以后我得跟您学习
once work is over,
这个 一旦工作结束了
I will just enjoy a glass of wine
就踏踏实实地喝杯酒
[and put work matters]
这个工作的事
[behind me.]
都抛在脑后
Let myself have a fully relax,
让自己充分地放松一下
and empty all the trivial things
把脑子里边内存
out of my mind
都清空了
to work better
然后休息好
the next day.
为了第二天更好地工作
In the future, when you're free,
以后有空
you can invite me more often.
可以多找我
We'll be drinking companions from now on.
咱俩以后就是酒友了
Alright,
好的 好的 好的
Mr. Zhou,
周总
you've
那个
seen a lot,
您见多识广啊
I do have a question
我还真有一个问题
to ask you.
想问问您
What, your friend
怎么 你那个朋友
has another issue?
又有事了
Yes,
是
no, no, it's not.
不不不 也不是
it's just a
没有啊 就 就是一个
social issue.
社会问题啊
I figure it is a
我认为这是个
[You say now,]
您说现在
is there
是不是这个
more and more cradle snatchers?
姐弟恋它越来越多了
[And I don't understand,]
而且我就搞不明白啊
why do those young guys
那些年轻小伙子
insist on finding
他为什么就
an elder woman
非要找一个这个
with a family
拖家带口的
and children?
带着孩子的大姐姐呢
[What are they after?]
你说他图什么
Well, the issue you mentioned,
你说的这个问题吧
I think,
我觉得这个
young guys
年轻的小伙子呢
have a purer view of love.
他的爱情观比较纯粹
Look, they don't care any conditions,
你看 他不看什么条件
no matter how old the woman is,
他不管这个人多大年龄
and whether she's been married before,
也不管她是没结过婚
even don't care if she has children.
也不管她是不是有孩子
He must be very pure.
他很纯粹
He only cares about the person.
他只看这个人
But then,
不是 那
you know,
那 那你说
the elder woman
人这小姐姐吧
has already married with
那都已经跟别人
other people
开过花了
and even has their kids.
都结出果来了
[How can he]
你说你还
[still hook up her like this?]
这么着去追人家
[Even without any reaction,]
完了之后人家还不理他
he still actively helps
然后他还
to take care of her children.
主动帮人带孩子
I think
我认为
he must be after something.
他一定是图点什么
[Maybe he's after]
可能是图人家
[her wealth,]
小姐姐的财产
and wants to make himself
想要让他自己
earn more wealth by it.
少奋斗二十年
That's not necessarily the case.
那也未必啊
The woman who has been
凡是离过婚
divorced and has children
有过孩子的女人
will be more pragmatic.
会更加的务实
Additionally, there is
再说还有
legal protection for personal property.
法律保护个人财产
It's not that easy to cheat money.
哪那么容易分钱呀
That's true.
也是啊
There's also the law
还有法律在这儿
to protect it.
保护着呢
And
而且我这朋友
the friend of mine,
我的这个
I know her very well,
我非常了解她
[you know.]
知道吧
[She's a]
她还是一个
[fairly calm person.]
比较冷静的人
But I don't understand,
但是我就不明白
this young guy,
你说这小伙子
what is he after?
他图什么
This actually shows that
这倒恰恰说明了
[the young guy is very mature mentally.]
这个小伙子心理很成熟
[He can look after her children.]
他还帮人带孩子
A young guy,
一个年轻的小伙子
can help a woman with her children.
能帮一个女人带孩子
What does this show?
这说明什么
This is true love.
这是真爱
[In today's society,]
现在的社会
[love can't withstand the test.]
爱情都经不住考验
The love that can withstand such tests
能经住这种考验的爱情
must be true love.
那就是真爱
Mr. Zhou,
不是 周总 你这
which side are you on?
你到底哪儿头的
What is your stance?
你到底什么立场啊
Of course, I'm on your side.
我当然跟你一头的啊
So...
合着你这这这
you can talk
这正着也能聊
from both sides?
反着你也能聊啊
You asked for my opinion,
你问我的看法
I'm telling it like it is.
我实话实说呀
[Really, this is true love]
真的 这真的是真爱
[in my opinion.]
我觉得
Whatever, let's finish it.
也行吧 干杯吧
I...should go first.
我我 我先走了
No more drink?
不喝了
I have to work tomorrow.
我明儿还得工作呢
Goodbye, Mr. Zhou. Good night.
周总再见 晚安
Alright, take care.
行 行 慢走啊
Done.
洗好啦
Look at the skin,
这小皮肤
just like a peeled egg.
跟剥了壳的鸡蛋似的
Don't touch me.
你别碰我
I'm your mom.
我是你妈
What's wrong with touching you?
摸摸你怎么了
Don't be handsy.
你别动手动脚的
[I'm still upset about the case]
你糊弄我那事
you fooled me.
我没消气呢
Dad,
爸
[are you packed?]
收拾好了吗
[Notebooks, books, test papers,]
本 书 卷子
[all set.]
齐活
Alright, thank you, Dad.
好嘞 谢谢老爸
Dad, good job.
老爸辛苦啦
Yunjie, look,
云阶 我告诉你啊
you're fourteen now.
十四岁了
You should do it by yourself.
自己的书包自己整理
I can't pack for you
我还能给你
all the time.
收拾一辈子啊
Okay.
好
Dad,
老爸
the more time you help me pack,
你多帮我整理一天
the more time I'll love you.
我就多爱你一天
Mwah.
么么哒
That's too much.
太过分了
Alright, that's enough.
行了 差不多了
Stop acting, she left.
别演了 走了
What's the matter?
干什么 这是
The atmosphere was quite good
刚才看电视
just now while watching TV.
气氛不是挺好的吗
War between women,
女人之间的战争
you won't understand.
你不懂
War?
战争啊
Then I'll stay out of it.
那我躲远点
It's too scary.
太可怕了
Be careful not to get hit by mistake.
小心误伤
Sleep.
睡觉
Good night.
晚安
[Don't stay up late.]
赶紧睡觉啊
Milk.
牛奶
Did you comfort her alone?
你是不单独哄她了
Just a kid,
孩子嘛
a little comfort isn't big deal.
你哄两句就完了
Besides,
再说这个事
we were wrong to hide it in the beginning,
我们瞒着她有错在先
[right?]
是吧
[Look,]
你看
[I just took advantage of checking]
我趁着给她查作业
her homework to comfort her a bit,
稍微哄两句
and it'll be fine, won't it?
不就好了吗
That's all?
就这些
And then gave her a piece of chocolate.
顺便再给她塞块巧克力
I knew it,
我就知道
what's wrong with you?
你怎么回事啊
You are always the good person,
好人都让你做了
and I'm the only one
这家里边
playing the bad cop in this family.
就我一人唱白脸啊
Don't worry.
没事 没事
I'll play the bad cop in the future.
以后我唱白脸
Alright?
好吧
I will.
我唱
Old bad cop.
老白脸
I'm your old bad cop.
老白脸也是你的嘛
Come on,
去去去
go to sleep.
睡觉去
Are you
你 不睡觉
staring at the phone
你瞅着这手机
and trying to meditate?
发功啊
Xin hasn't
心心到现在
sent me a message yet.
都没给我来个消息
Maybe Haowen is at home
没准现在老贾
kneeling on a washboard right now,
在家里面跪搓衣板呢
So she has no time to answer you.
没工夫搭理你
You
不是
didn't see it?
你是没见着
They had a big fight today.
他俩今天吵得挺凶的
I think Haowen is really angry.
我觉得老贾是真生气了
He is really angry?
老贾真生气
How dare him!
他胆子大了
He dares to be angry?
他还敢真生气啊
What will he do when he's angry?
他真生气什么样啊
Never seen it.
没见过
When a child is quiet,
小孩静悄悄
he must be up to something.
必定在作妖
You're overthinking.
你想多了
Xin is already mature enough.
心心都多大了
She's almost a second-time mom.
都快是二胎妈了
Xin,
心心啊
has Haowen back home yet?
老贾回家了没有啊
No matter how old she is,
她多大在我眼里
she's still a child in my eyes.
也是个小孩
Do you think she has
你说她该不会是
depression during pregnancy now?
孕期抑郁症了吧
Impossible.
不可能
Even if
她
she has depression,
就算是抑郁症
she has Haowen.
也有老贾呢
As long as you're not, it's fine.
你不要抑郁就好了
[He's back.]
他回来啦
[We were taking a walk downstairs.]
我们在楼下散步呢
See, what I said?
你看看我说什么
It's their own business,
人夫妻俩的事
There's no need to be worried.
你操什么心啊
How should I do things
我也是绝了
that make me neither
这一天天的
fish nor fowl everyday.
净干这里外不是人的事
[Exercise?]
偷着练呢
Is the door closed?
大门关了吗
No, it's not.
没有呢
I'll close it.
我去关去
Just let me do it.
我去关去吧
Xin,
心心
[why you are back now?]
你怎么这么晚回来呀
You're not asleep yet?
你们没睡啊
Hurry up,
你快快快
why are you backing so late at night?
大晚上怎么回来了
[Haowen's...mom came.]
我 我婆婆来了
[Dad, help me.]
爸帮我拿
[So]
婆婆来啦
[I don't need to]
婆婆来了
[take care of the kids now.]
我就不用带孩子啦
[You know the character of her.]
你知道我婆婆这人吧
[she's a good person,]
人是挺好的
[but her educational philosophy]
但是教育理念
[is different from mine.]
跟我不一样啊
[So, you know...]
那你说
[Conflict again.]
又吵架了
[I don't know]
我这说也不是
[how to handle it.]
不说也不是
[So,]
拉倒
[I come back home.]
赶紧回家
[It's good]
回家好
to be home,
回家多享清福啊
and enjoy some leisure.
给自己放几天假 是吧
Yes.
是
Just let her
正好 让你婆婆
get close to her grandson.
好好亲近亲近大孙子
Exactly.
就是 就是
I'm hungry.
我饿了
What do you want to eat?
想吃啥
There are many foods in the fridge.
冰箱里啥都有
Wontons.
小馄饨
Be quick.
快快快
Wait for a moment.
爸给你做去啊
These past two days have worn me out.
这两天把我演得太累了
Honey,
老婆
I used to
我以前觉得
think that the acting
那电视里面演的呀
on TV is so
这都是什么
simple.
太简单了
But now I've
但是现在我
changed my mind.
改变这种想法了
I think acting
我觉得表演
is not simple.
不简单
You're better than them.
你比他们强
Aren't they all saying
不都说了吗
that those who act in life
生活中演戏的
are the real actors?
那才叫真演员
You've outperformed them.
你把他们秒了
What about you?
那你呢
Let me interview you.
我采访采访你呀
How do you feel now?
你现在什么感受
To be honest?
说实话吗
Wronged.
委屈
What are you wronged about?
你委屈什么
I feel wronged for my daughter.
替我闺女委屈
What grievance can she have?
我闺女那更没委屈了
Look at her,
你看她每天的
she can't be happy and healthy more.
跳跳蹦蹦 健健康康的
She's a happy angel.
她就是个快乐天使啊
Come on.
什么快乐天使啊
You don't understand.
你不懂
Being the eldest child is very wronged.
做老大很委屈的
In short,
简单地说啊
if the second one makes some trouble,
老二闯祸了
don't you have to take the blame?
你是不是得替他扛
If he's wronged,
他受委屈了
don't you have to comfort him?
你是不得哄他
If he's disobedient,
他不听话了
don't you have to discipline him?
你还得管着他
And he's still unhappy.
人家还不高兴
Just
梦心
think about Mengxin,
你想想梦心
understand?
懂吧
As soon as I think about Yunjie's life,
我一想云阶这辈子
she's going to suffer my experience.
都要走我的老路
Wait a minute,
等会儿
what did you say?
你说什么
The grievances of the eldest?
老大的委屈
Then what about the second child?
那我们老二的委屈呢
Enough.
行了
what grievances can he has?
老二有什么委屈的呀
The bitterness of the second kid
老二的委屈
is deeper than the sea.
那个苦比海都深哪
That's enough.
你行了
Don't be ungrateful for your happiness.
别身在福中不知福了啊
I tell you,
我跟你说
when I think about this,
我一想到这事
I feel very wronged.
我就很委屈啊
In short,
简单地说
the second child,
老二
in addition to mom and dad,
除了爸妈管你之外
there's also an elder sister or brother
还有一个老大
who's watching over you
一直盯着你
and restraining you.
死死地拿捏着你
Isn't it good?
不好吗
Is it good?
好吗
Just tell me,
我就问你
when Mengxin was young,
梦心小时候
did she ever wear
有没有穿过
clothes you've worn?
你穿过的衣服
Yes, so?
穿 穿过啊
Me, too.
我也穿过
You wore your sister's clothes?
你是姐啊
Yeah,
对呀
I did wear her clothes
她是我姐呀
and went to school.
我穿着我姐的衣服上学
Isn't that embarrassing?
丢不丢人哪
Didn't they tailor them at all?
都不改一下吗
Yes, but...
它 它改
they're still women's clothes.
它也是个女款哪
The clothes I wore
衣服
were second-hand.
我穿的二手的
The things I used
用的
were second-hand,
我用的二手的
even the food I ate
甚至于我吃的
was second-hand.
也是二手的
All were second-hand.
都是二手的
Am I second-hand?
我是个二手的吗
What about me?
我是二手的吗
No, you're not.
你 你不是
She has no comments
就你这件事
on our relation.
她没有意见啊
And
那
anything else?
还有吗
Even now
还有
she's still in control of me
到现在她还管着我
and you,
她还管着你
right?
是不是
She even controls the dispensing
她还给你
of medicines.
配药
Right?
有没有
Remote control.
遥控
Is it uncomfortable?
难不难受
But I can understand her.
但我挺能理解大姐的
Being the eldest sister is not easy.
当老大也不容易的
So you second children's actions
合着你们当老二的作
are all about the desire to survive,
都是求生欲闹的呀
and want to be noticed, right?
想刷存在感是吧
Isn't that troublesome?
那这不麻烦了吗
If both children
那要俩孩子
have grievances,
都有委屈的话
should we still
咱这老二还
have the second child?
还生吗
Why not?
生啊
Honey, there will be no such problems
老婆 我们家没问题啊
in our family for sure.
我们家当然没有问题
For our family, having two children
我们家生两个孩子
has no problem at all.
一点问题都没有
Just take it easy.
你放心吧
Anyone has grievances.
委屈嘛 谁没有过
Isn't it?
对吧
That's true.
也是
It's not even a grievance for a family.
一家人那都算不上委屈
But then again,
但是话得说回来
as for the education
关于以后
of our children in the future,
孩子的教育问题啊
if they have conflicts
他们在家
at home,
如果产生了矛盾
let them resolve it by themselves.
让他们自行解决
We shouldn't interfere.
我们不要管
If they can't solve it
如果解决不了
and ask us,
问到咱们了
then our four family members
那我们一家四口
will discuss it together.
一起共同协商
Okay?
行吗
Okay.
同意
Be fair.
公平
Be democratic.
民主
Build a harmonious home.
共建和谐家园
Yes.
对
When you are available,
等有空的时候
go back to mom's home and take a look.
你回咱妈那儿看一眼
Are the things
就是以前
Yunjie used
云阶用过的东西
still there?
还在不在
Let's just
咱们给她
throw all away.
断 舍 离了
We definitely don't have any.
咱家肯定是没有了
What an era it is now!
这都什么年代了
Life is affluent, right?
日子都好了 好吧
And Yunjie is fourteen already.
这云阶都十四了
Even if we want to use it, it's no way.
想用你也用不上啊
Uh...
你这
I'm really overthinking.
我真的是想多了呀
Let's sleep?
睡觉吧
Okay.
睡啊
Well,
那
sleep.
睡呗
We
睡了
don't feel wronged when falling asleep.
什么委屈都没有了是吧
So comfortable.
舒坦
It's really nice to be home.
回家真好
Everything tastes good.
吃什么都舒服
Just eat more.
你多吃点啊
I need to make my little grandson
我得让我的小外孙
sturdy.
结实点
Dad, look at mom,
爸 你看我妈
she only cares about her grandson
只关注我肚子里的
and doesn't care about me at all.
根本不在乎我
Well, paying attention to it
那我关注他
is also caring about you, isn't it?
不就是关注你吗
Alright, I'm full and satisfied.
行了 吃饱喝足了
I'm going to sleep.
我准备睡觉去了
Tomorrow morning,
明天早上
when you two are exercising,
您二老锻炼的时候
please keep it down.
声音小一点啊
Don't disturb me,
不要打搅我
let me have a good sleep, okay?
让我睡个安稳觉 好吗
Okay, just
快去 快去 快去
go to bed.
睡觉
Good night.
晚安
What time is it?
几点了
Did they have another argument
你说大半夜的
in the middle of night?
是不又吵架了
This isn't the first time.
这也不是第一次了
Tomorrow
明天咱们
we'll have cherries to eat again.
又有车厘子吃了
Every time Haowen comes to pick her up,
那浩文每次来接她
doesn't he buy us
不都是给咱们
a box of cherries?
买一盒车厘子吗
Then they two
然后两个人
chat in the room for a while.
在屋里头聊一会儿
And then go back
好 唱着歌跳着舞
happily.
回家了
That's true.
那倒是
Well.
走吧
Just go back to sleep.
回去睡觉吧
Sleep.
睡觉
Don't always
别老这样
be like that.
老这样是干啥呀
How funny it is.
真是 真有意思
Go, go, go.
快快快
Okay, sleep, sleep, sleep.
行 睡觉睡觉睡觉
Stop it, I'm tired today.
别撒娇了 今天我累了
Rice cakes are coming.
米粿来啦
Rice cakes?
还有米粿呢
Aunt Lanxiang.
兰香表姑
I've grown so tall,
我长这么高
it must because when I was little,
肯定都是因为我小时候
you fed me really well.
你给我吃得特别好
That makes sense.
有道理啊
Then keep eating more.
那你接着多吃点
Look at Aunt Lanxiang,
你看看人兰香表姑
she made such a sumptuous meal.
做得这么丰盛
Look,
你看看
look.
看看
You are saying that
你是不想说
she cooks better than me.
她做得比我好
Today, sit in the back seat.
今天坐后排
I want to take the passenger seat.
爸 我想坐前面嘛
With mom's condition,
就我妈那状态
can I sit in the passenger seat
我以后是不是
every time in the future?
都能坐副驾了呀
Do you have any kind of complex
你是不是对副驾
about the passenger seat?
有什么情结啊
It has a good view.
副驾视野好呀
Although I can't drive,
虽然我不会开车
I still have that sense of control.
但仍然有那种驾驭感
Then what about the food I cook,
那我做的饭
also has a sense of control.
也有驾驭感
You're going out?
你要出门啊
Work.
上班啊
Aren't you on vacation?
你不是休假了吗
What vacation?
休什么呀
The doctor said I'm almost ready.
大夫都说我差不多了
I have to go back to work quickly.
我得赶快上班去了
I can't be like your dad,
我可不能学你爸
slacking off every day.
天天摸鱼
Have you been slacking off recently?
你最近摸鱼了吗
I just wanna sit in the passenger seat.
我就想坐个副驾
Why is it so difficult?
怎么就这么难呀
It's not difficult.
不难
[To protect your mom,]
为了保护你妈
let her sit in the back seat.
让她坐后边
Agree.
同意
We love you.
我们爱你啊
Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
婉婉 真真
Food is ready.
快 出来吃饭了
He Lu,
何璐
We're about to enter the campus,
马上进校园了
hurry up and put your phone away.
快把手机收起来吧
We're still outside the school.
这在学校外面呢
Leave me alone.
别管我
Rules of the school,
学校规定
remember to put it away.
快收起来啊
Alright, alright, I know.
好好好 知道了
Don't tell the teacher.
别告诉老师啊
Don't worry.
放心吧
[Baby Lu, I'm here.]
璐宝 我来啦
You're in a good mood today.
你今天心情不错嘛
I thought you'd be unhappy
我还以为你因为
because of what happened
昨天你妈的事情
with your mom yesterday.
不高兴呢
You change your mood so fast.
翻脸比翻书还快呀
You're so good at talking.
哪壶不开提哪壶
I just forget it.
我都忘了这茬了
Thanks for reminding me again.
非得提醒我是吧
I'm just showing concern for you.
我这是关心你
I even asked
我还跟我爸
my dad for 200 yuan
要了两百块钱呢
only to
就为了
treat you to a big meal to comfort you.
请你吃大餐安抚你
Are you
你是不是
using the excuse of comforting me
打着安抚我的旗号
to get money from your dad?
找你爸要的钱啊
I'm just looking out for you, okay?
我就为了你好嘛
You don't want to eat?
你不想吃啊
Well, then I'm leaving.
不吃我走了
No, no, no, I'm still internally hurt.
别别别 我这是内伤
and still need some comfort.
还是很需要安抚的
Alright.
好好好
[Just tell your parents that]
你赶快跟你爸妈说一声
[you won't be home for dinner.]
晚上不回去吃饭了
I'll treat you with a good meal.
我请你吃点好的
Okay.
好嘞
Li Yunjie,
李云阶
what good stuff will you eat?
吃什么好吃的
Come on.
快走 快走
I'm going to school,
我去上学校
flowers are smiling at me.
花儿对我笑
Birds are chirping "Good morning,
小鸟说 早早早
why do you have a small backpack on?"
你为什么背着小书包
[Miss Chen.]
陈小姐
[Dr. Yu, morning.]
俞医生早
What a coincidence.
这么巧
Morning, Wanwan, Zhenzhen.
早啊 婉婉 真真
Morning, uncle doctor.
医生叔叔早
Morning.
早
Uncle doctor,
医生叔叔
have you finished your homework?
你的功课做完了吗
Not yet, what should I do?
还没有呢 怎么办
Then why are you still running here?
那你还在这儿跑步
Well, balance work and leisure.
劳逸结合嘛
Uncle doctor,
医生叔叔
learning is your own business.
学习是自己的事情
We can't help you with that.
我们帮不了你
You have to strive it on your own.
你要自己加油
Come on.
加油
Alright, I will.
好嘞 我加油
Dr. Yu,
俞医生
you left your notebook at my home.
你的笔记本还落我家了
I'll send them to the school bus first,
我先送她们上校车
and give it to you later.
一会儿给你
Okay, just take your time.
好 不着急 你先忙
Uncle doctor, goodbye.
医生叔叔 再见
Bye.
拜拜
Take care.
好好上学啊
Listen to the teachers!
听老师的话啊
Got it.
好
Guess who I just saw.
你们猜我刚看谁了
Who?
谁啊
Director Xu.
许总监
How could it be?
怎么可能
Isn't she on vacation?
她不是休假吗
Don't you believe me?
你不信啊
I couldn't make such a silly mistake.
我怎么可能认错人
Director Xu.
许总监
Morning, Director Xu.
许总监早
Good morning, everyone.
大家早 大家早
Director Xu, aren't you on vacation?
许总监 你不休假啦
I lay at home for a week,
在家躺了一个礼拜
making my back hurt so much.
躺得我腰都疼
So I come back
回公司
to exercise a bit.
锻炼锻炼
Are you okay?
你们还好吧
Yes.
好
Well, carry on.
好 忙吧
See?
看见没
That's the boss.
领导就是领导
Hard work isn't just a slogan
努力工作在老大那儿
for our boss.
真不是句口号
Fighting.
努力工作
Dr. Yu.
俞医生
Miss Chen.
陈小姐
Thank you.
谢谢
I should be the one appreciating.
我还得谢谢你呢
You accompanied my children so late.
昨天陪孩子到那么晚
Well,
这事
I hope you don't mind.
我希望你不要介意啊
I just saw that
我是看到
the children were unwilling to
孩子们不肯
open the door for that little girl.
给那个小姑娘开门
After I confirmed her identity,
我确认过她身份以后
then I brought her up.
才带她上来的
And the kids wanted to play with me,
正好孩子们想跟我玩
so I stayed.
我就留下了
I know.
我知道
But I still have to thank you.
但是我还得谢谢你
You're so busy with work everyday,
你平时工作那么忙
it took up your rest time.
耽误你的休息时间了
It's okay.
没事
I like kids anyway.
我本来就喜欢孩子嘛
Otherwise, why would I
不然我干吗
choose major in pediatrics, right?
选儿科方向 对不对
Hello, are you Chen Wanzhen?
你好 陈婉真吗
Yes, I am.
是我
Your books, please check.
您的书 请查收
Alright, thank you.
好嘞 谢谢啊
You bought so many books.
买这么多书啊
I signed up for a class.
报了一个班
[Really?]
是吗
Are you still taking classes?
你现在还在上课
Just a hobby class.
业余的
I can't compare with a doctor
跟你这个博士啊
like you.
没法比
I heard from Wanwan that
我听婉婉说
you used to be a top student, too.
你之前也是个学霸啊
Don't take it seriously.
哪有啊
The things I've learned,
我这学的东西啊
I've given it all back to teachers.
都丢给老师了
So I need to start learning again.
我得重新学起
You have classes and work,
你要上课又要上班
that's so busy.
那么忙
How about let me take care of the kids?
要不然我帮你带孩子
Thank you,
不用
I can manage on my own.
我自己可以的
Don't get me wrong.
你别误会
I didn't mean that.
我不是那个意思
I mean,
我 我是说
I could take them out
我可以带她们出去
to the interest classes or something.
上兴趣班什么的
I won't be alone
我不会单独
with them.
跟她们在一起
If you're worried,
你要不放心的话
I can have aunt accompany us.
我可以让阿姨陪着一起
I'm not worried.
我不是不放心
I just think it's too much trouble.
我是觉得太麻烦你了
You doctors already have
你们医生工作
a demanding work,
本来就辛苦
and you're also studying.
而且你还要读书
I've already hired a full-time nanny
我已经给她们请了
for them.
全天的阿姨
It's not a big deal.
可以的
Then I'll go back to my room first.
那我就先回屋了
Okay, bye.
好好 我不打扰你
Bye.
拜拜
Thank you.
谢谢你啊
Did the surgery fail?
手术是不是失败了
What do you mean by fail?
什么叫失败了呀
The front desk said you come back
前台说你假都没休完
early before your leave is over.
就提前回来上班了
[why else would you be back?]
不是失败是什么
Yes, failed,
失败了 失败了
failed.
失败了
Why do you come back early?
你提前回来干吗呀
At least you take your vacation over.
好歹你也把假休完哪
Since I'm planning to have a baby,
那我都打算生孩子了
aren't I supposed to hurry back
还不得赶紧滚回来
to work?
工作呀
You want to work, right?
要工作是吧
Alright, then I'm leaving.
那行 我走了
No, no, no.
别别别
Just sit down.
坐会儿 坐会儿
Come on.
来来来
Just tell me,
跟我扒一扒
what happened in the company
我不在这几天
while I was away.
公司都什么情况啊
The headhunter recommended
猎头那边
a few deputy directors to Zhang.
给老张推荐了
None of them
几个副总监
were suitable.
都不靠谱
What about Huang Sisi?
黄思思呢
No news for a long time.
早就没下文了
She's on the same level
她在蓝海
as me at Blue Ocean.
跟我也算是平级的
It's probably hard to negotiate.
估计条件不好谈
She can't compare with you.
她跟你可没法比
Everyone in the industry knows
业内都知道
about her and Yu Hai.
她跟于海的事
Without the platform of Blue Ocean,
离开蓝海的平台
her true worth
她自己几斤几两
will be revealed.
那不就露馅了
We can't say that.
话也不能这么说的
What if she's a rising star?
那万一人家是个后浪呢
Then you, a veteran, should be careful.
那您这前浪可得小心了
[Since you wanna have a second child,]
既然要生二胎
it's time to focus on building a team.
梯队建设得抓紧了
Promoting Mu should be
提拔阿木那事得
put on the agenda.
提上日程了
I'll go to Zhang's office and
我先去老张那儿去
drop some hints.
吹吹风去
Thank you
谢谢你啊
for standing with me.
跟我站一头
No.
不
I'm doing this for the stability
我这是为了公司的
and unity of the company.
安定团结
Then tell me the truth.
那你跟我说实话
Are you really afraid that
其实你是不是特别怕
I'll have a second child
我生二胎
and quit my job?
从此撂挑子不干了
No, no, no.
不不不 不
You're overthinking it.
那你可想多了
I'm afraid of those young people.
我怕的是那些年轻人
They might disrupt the workplace
分分钟给我整顿职场
at any moment and leave.
拍屁股走人
As for someone like you,
就您这种
a middle-aged person with family,
拖家带口的中年人
soon to have another mouth to feed,
马上还多一张吃饭的嘴
would you dare to resign?
你敢辞职吗
Why would I be afraid of you?
我怕你什么呀
It seems a little bit reasonable.
好像是没什么可怕的
You have a good grasp of psychology.
你这心理拿捏得挺准哪
For sure.
那是
Who am I?
我干什么的呀
I'm professional.
我是专业的
Impressive.
厉害
Respect.
佩服
Mr. Zhang.
张总
You're back.
你回来了
Why didn't you
不 你怎么
tell me beforehand?
不跟我说一声呢
I have some issue,
正好有事
come with me.
你跟我来一趟
Officially back to work.
正式上班了
Look at you,
你看看
your complexion
这个假休得
is much better after the leave.
气色都好了
I just get excited
我主要是一回公司
as soon as I'm back.
就精神亢奋
I have a
我这儿有一个
real estate project here
这个华謃地产的
from Hua Xiang Real Estate.
一个地产项目
Take a look at the project document.
这个项目书你看看
[Real estate project.]
地产项目
We might need to visit the site.
可能还要去实地吧
Well,
要不然这样
I'll go there
一会儿我就
later with my team.
带人过去看看
You're still so reliable
还是老员工
and can always provide the efficiency.
办事效率就是高
[Alright,]
行
[you do the field inspection,]
你实地考察
I'll
我呢
arrange to meet with Mr. Qian.
去约钱总
Let's make a concentrated effort
这几天一鼓作气
these days and get the project.
把他拿下
Okay,
好
I will go back.
那我先去了
Thank you, sir.
谢谢师傅
Take care.
慢走
Bye.
好嘞
Xiongxiong.
熊熊
Grandma,
奶奶
grandma, I miss you.
奶奶 我想你了
Sweetheart,
宝贝
I miss you too.
奶奶也想你啊
Xiongxiong,
熊熊
why didn't you go to school today?
今天怎么没去上学啊
Dad and mom are getting a divorce,
我爸我妈都要离婚了
how can I still go to school?
我还上什么学呀
Divorce?
离婚
Haowen.
浩文
Mom.
妈
What happened between you and Xin?
你跟心心怎么了
Why are you here?
您怎么来了
What's going on?
这怎么了
I bumped into something.
妈 我自己撞的
Crap!
瞎说
Did Xin hit you?
被心心打的吧
It's not, mom.
什么呀 妈
Just stay out of it.
您就别掺和了
Look at this,
你看看
how could she hit so hard?
下手怎么这么狠呢
It is really...
真是
It must be painful.
打成这样
Mom.
妈
It's not a hit.
哪儿是打的 您这
I just feel bad for you.
心疼死妈了
It's okay, mom.
没事 妈
Why are you so timid?
你咋这么窝囊呢
Getting hit by a woman.
被媳妇打
Don't talk like that, mom.
说什么呢 妈
Look at you.
看看你
Doesn't it hurt?
不疼啊
Not at all, mom.
不疼 妈
Did Xin get up yet?
心心起来了吗
Not yet.
没呢
Don't worry.
别急
Haowen will come soon.
一会儿浩文就来了
[Mrs. Xu,]
亲家母
[are you at home?]
在家吗
Here I am.
我来了
We are home.
亲家
Mrs. Xu.
亲家母
are you here?
您怎么来了
Welcome.
亲家母来了
I just come to visit you.
我来看看你们
No need to bring gifts.
买这么些东西
Just take a sit.
快坐 快坐 快坐
Okay, thank you.
好好好
Let me take a look.
我先看看
Please sit down.
快坐 快坐 快坐
Thank you.
好好好
You come here alone?
你一个人啊
Yes.
我一个人
Well, sit down.
快坐 快坐 快坐
Okay.
好好好
Alright,
那这样 这样
you two chat,
你们姐儿俩聊
I'll go buy some groceries.
我去买点菜
It's really bothering you.
真是辛苦你
Just sit here.
快坐 快坐 快坐
Come on.
坐坐 快坐 快坐
Have a rest.
坐下 坐下
[Okay.]
好好好
Thank you.
辛苦 辛苦
Why are you
亲家母啊
getting younger and younger?
你怎么越长越年轻了呀
Really?
怎么会呢
Your complexion is getting better.
我看你是气色越来越好
Just so so.
还行
This courtyard
亲家母
is well maintained,
这小院是打理得啊
and is getting better and better.
现在是越来越好了
So comfortable.
真舒适啊
Look at this,
你看看
this rockery, rocks,
这是假山 石头
water,
有水
and trees.
还有树
It's all thanks to my husband.
这都是老许的功劳
So nice.
真好 真好
Didn't
亲家
your old house
你老家那个房子
also get turned into a big villa?
不是也翻成大别墅了吗
Yes.
是是是
It must be comfortable, too.
肯定也很舒服
thanks to the children.
托孩子的福
So...
亲家母啊
Did Xin come back yesterday?
昨天心心回来了
Yes.
是 是
She's pregnant, you know,
这不怀孕了吗
so she gets tired easily.
容易犯困
and she hasn't gotten up yet.
这不现在还没起来呢
So we let her sleep a bit longer.
让她多睡会儿
The doctor said that
亲家母啊
those who are about to
人医生可是说了
give birth can't always
快要生产的人哪
lie down.
不能老躺着
[They need to do more exercises,]
得出来活动活动
[which is good for the delivery.]
要不然不利于生产
Just take it easy.
亲家
[Xin doesn't have time]
我们心心哪有时间
[to always lie down.]
老躺着呀
You see,
你看
Haowen is so busy all the time.
浩文每天忙得都不着家
Nearly all the housework
那家里家外 上上下下
is done by her alone.
全她一个人忙活